JOHN ANTHONY BALBIN

Software Engineer

- **+639497724252**
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/jabalbin/
- San Vicente St. Sto. Domingo, Albay, Philippines
- swengr.johnbalbin@gmail.com
- https://swengr-janan.github.io/



EXPERIENCE

Lead Quality Assurance Specialist

Astra Interactive Studios

- · Perform manual testing on various products, including blockchainintegrated games.
- Develop and execute test cases, scripts, and plans; identify, document, and track bugs.
- Validate smart contracts and blockchain interactions, ensuring seamless performance.
- Collaborate with stakeholders to define and document clear, testable system requirements.
- Monitor developers' progress on GitHub, lead developer meetings, and conduct quality checks on the company's website.

Software Engineer

MetaGaming Guild

= 09/2023 - 04/2024 Legazpi, Albay, Philippines

- Design and execute test plans, cases, and scripts to identify software defects in game development.
- Conduct thorough regression testing to ensure game stability after bug fixes or updates.
- Collaborate with game designers, developers, and artists to provide quality and user experience feedback.
- Create and maintain documentation for testing processes, bug tracking, and test results.
- Participate in cross-functional meetings to discuss and resolve QArelated concerns and improvements.

Software Engineer

SparkPoint Technologies Inc

- Create project documentations, evaluate, analyze, and define requirements for blockchain-integrated software/web applications.
- Write, test, update, and maintain source code and APIs; perform system maintenance and identify software issues.
- Develop software verification plans, QA standards, and procedures; perform UAT, user experience, and regression testing.
- Conduct daily scrum meetings, guide junior developers, and document issues on GitHub and JIRA.

Software Engineer

TechnoPro Engineering

iii 12/2019 - 12/2020 ♀ Shinagawa, Tokyo, Japan

- Gather data, analyze requirements, and perform system analysis before project initiation.
- Create wireframes, prototypes, UI/UX designs, and user flow
- Develop, update, and maintain project documentation and technology stack identification.
- Write, test, and maintain code; conduct comprehensive testing and quality assessments.
- Collaborate with developers, present daily progress, and maintain website and source code.

SUMMARY

With over 7 years of experience in Software Engineering and Quality Assurance, I excel in integrating disciplines for exceptional results. My meticulous testing methodologies and use of cutting-edge tools ensure rigorous testing, swift defect identification, and continuous improvement for superior user experiences.

TRAINING/CERTIFICATIONS

ICT Skills Assessment (Software Engineer) Australian Computer Society

Agile Development Practices

LinkedIn Learning

Foundations of Project Management

Google on Coursera

Front-end Web Development with React

Coursera

Career Service Examination (Professional)

Civil Service Commission

LANGUAGES

English

Superior



EDUCATION

BS in Information Technology

Bicol University

Secondary

Sto. Domingo National High School

Primary

Sto. Domingo Central School

iii 01/2003 - 01/2009 ♀ Sto. Domingo, Albay

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Denso Techno Philippines Inc

- Review, compare, and evaluate source code and specifications.
- · Create pattern designs to identify project scope and limitations.
- Identify and prepare the test environment and procedures; perform automated tests and debugging.
- Simulate and analyze test results; develop tools to enhance quality and productivity.
- Maintain system documentation, standards, and procedures; provide feedback on software improvements and train junior engineers.

Powered by Shancy